Inventory of the Elisabeth Burgos-Debray papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Elisabeth Burgos-Debray papers
1920-2007
2001C89
Hoover Institution Archives
20 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 2 card file boxes (12.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, sound recordings and transcripts of interviews, and printed matter relating to the trial of the French revolutionary journalist Régis Debray in Bolivia; revolutionary movements and political conditions in Bolivia, Cuba, Venezuela and elsewhere in Latin America; women in Cuba; and the Guatemalan Indian leader Rigoberta Menchú.
Burgos-Debray, Elisabeth
Access
Box 27 closed during the lifetime of E. Burgos-Debray. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001, with an increment received in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1941 Born, Valencia, Venezuela
1967-1970 Active in campaign for the release of Régis Debray from prison in Bolivia
1980s Works for the French government as head of the Instituto Cultural Francés in Seville and as a cultural attaché in Madrid
1982-1983 Interviews Rigoberta Menchú and collaborates on the book Me llamo Rigoberta Menchú y asì me nació la conciencia
1983 Awarded Premio Casa de las Americas
Scope and Content of Collection
The Elisabeth Burgos-Debray papers contain materials largely pertaining to Latin America in the past forty-five years, with a particular emphasis on the history of guerrilla movements in the 1960s and 1970s; the experience of civil war in Guatemala in the 1970s and 1980s; and aspects of political and social life in Cuba during the Castro era. Consisting of correspondence, writings, and numerous recorded interviews, the papers reflect the personal biography and career of Burgos-Debray, who in her youth was active in the radical politics of Latin America in the 1960s. She later became an anthropologist and journalist, while also collaborating on a number of books relating to Guatemala and Cuba.
In 1967, Burgos-Debray married Régis Debray, a French intellectual then imprisoned in Bolivia on charges of having aided Che Guevara's ill fated guerrilla campaign in that country. Debray's case became a cause célèbre in France and elsewhere, and an international effort was undertaken to secure his release. The substantial Régis Debray File in the papers includes letters written from prison by Debray to Elisabeth Burgos-Debray, as well as the extensive correspondence conducted by Debray's parents on their son's behalf. There is also a large quantity of clippings in this file relating to Debray's trial and imprisonment, many of which also contain details on the capture and execution of Guevara by the Bolivian military.
Régis Debray and Elisabeth Burgos-Debray were later divorced, and Burgos-Debray pursued her academic studies in France. In 1982, her interviews with a Guatemalan woman, Rigoberta Menchú, formed the basis of a book, Me llamo Rigoberta Menchú y así me nació la conciencia. In the work, which was translated into a number of languages, Menchú recounts her life story while describing the ravages of Guatemala's civil war in the 1970s and early 1980s as experienced by its indigenous population. Menchú's book later become the subject of controversy as to the veracity of certain passages and the exact circumstances of its creation. The Burgos-Debray papers contain drafts of the book (in the Speeches and Writings series) and recordings of the original interviews of Menchú done by Burgos-Debray (in the Sound Recordings series).
Speeches and Writings series contains a number of articles written by Burgos-Debray in recent years on issues of contemporary Latin American politics. These show the evolution in Burgos-Debray's political views from a position supportive of Fidel Castro's revolution to one of open criticism of human rights violations in Cuba. In the 1990s, Burgos-Debray transcribed and edited books by Daniel "Benigno" Alarcón Ramirez and Jorge Masetti, former Cuban officials who broke with Castro and went into exile. The papers contain drafts of these books (Works edited by Elisabeth Burgos-Debray series), as well as the original interviews on which they were based ( Sound Recordings series).
An important component of the collection is an extensive series of sound and video recordings of interviews conducted by Elisabeth Burgos-Debray with a wide range of Latin American political personalities ( Sound Recordings series, and Videorecordings series). The recordings are organized on the basis of their original arrangement by Burgos-Debray and are grouped by the name of the country they pertain to. Among the interviewees are former participants in guerrilla warfare in Venezuela, Guatemala, Colombia, and Peru, as well as several survivors of Che Guevara's rebel army in Bolivia. There are also interviews with former military officials involved in campaigns against these same guerrilla movements.
There are recordings of interviews with a number of prominent Cuban women, including officials in Castro's government. There are also many done with Cuban exiles, among them former political prisoners, human rights activists, and former combatants in the early period of armed struggle against the Castro government. There are also interviews conducted in recent years with political figures in Venezuela, including one with Hugo Chávez and others with members of the opposition to Chávez.
Debray, Régis.; Menchú, Rigoberta.; Audiotapes.; Bolivia--Politics and government.; Civil rights--Guatemala.; Cuba--Politics and government--1959-1990.; Guatemala--Politics and government.; Guerillas.; Indians of Central America--Guatemala.; Latin America--Politics and government--20th century.; Venezuela--Politics and government.; Women--Cuba.
- Biographical File, 1968-1985
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains clippings, itinerary, invitations, press pass, programs and map, and telegram, arranged by physical form.
  - Clippings, 1968-1985 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Itinerary relating to an official visit to Ecuador with Danielle Mitterrand, 1988 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Invitations to official gatherings and receptions in Cuba and France, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Press pass issued by Cuban authorities, 1980 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Programs and map relating to a trip to Cuba, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Telegram announcing the awarding of the Premio Casa de las Americas for the book Me llamo Rigoberta Menchú y así me nació la conciencia, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Correspondence, 1969-2000
  Contains letters and enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Letters of congratulation sent on the publication of the French and Spanish editions of the book Me llamo Rigoberta Menchú y así me nació la conciencia, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - General, 1974-1995
    - A-B, 1980-1992 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - C-D, 1976-1993 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - E-F, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - G-J, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - K-M, 1982-1994 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - N-P, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Q-S, 1980-1995 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - T-V, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - W-Z, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Unidentified, 1969-1993 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Aga Khan, Sadruddin, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Agee, Philip, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Agencia Literaria Carmen Balcells (Carmen Balcells, Alfonso Gómez Méndez, Gloria Gutiérrez, Carina Pons), 1988-1995 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Aguilar Castro, Joaquin Ricardo, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Aguilera, Gabriel, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Alberola, Octavio, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Alejandro, Ramón, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Alexandre-Debray, Janine, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Almendros, Rosa, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Andreoli, Marta, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Anselmo, Marielle, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Araújo Albrecht, Helena, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Arenas Sánchez, Rafael, 1984 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Arriola, Aura Marina, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Avicé, Edwige, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Bada, Ricardo, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Balcázar, Jaime, 1969-1985 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Ballón, Luis, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Balza, José, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Barker, Laurence, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Barloewen, Constantin von, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Baron Supervielle, Silvia, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Barreto Miliani, Oswaldo, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Barroeta, José, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Bejarano, Francisco, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Bergeret, Jean-Claude, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Bergman, Arlene Eisen, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Blackburn, Robin, 1974-1993 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Blaise, Suzanne, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Bourgonje, Fleur, 1997 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Buci-Glucksman, Christine, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Canby, Peter, 1999 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Carrera Damas, Germán, 1991 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Carvallo, Fernando, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Casal de Rey, Marta, 1978 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Casassa, Carmen, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Castillo, Carmen, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Castro, Fidel, 1974 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Castro Matos, Ignacio, 1996 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Coria, Clara, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - Davée, Annie, 1969-1981 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - David, Marc, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Daza, Sonia, 1994 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Díaz, Jesús, 1969-1993 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Díaz, Rafael-José, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Diaz de Arce, Mercy, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - Dong, Pham Van, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - Duno, Pedro, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - Durand, Rémy, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - Éditions Gallimard (F. Gaudry), 1989 (Box-folder 2: 35)
  - Eltit, Diamela, 1994 (Box-folder 2: 36)
  - Escobar, Filemón, 1971-1987 (Box-folder 2: 37)
  - Espejo Novoa, Paz, 1970-1991 (Box-folder 2: 38)
  - Faye, Jean-Pierre, 1988 (Box-folder 2: 39)
  - Fernández, Maruja, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 2: 40)
  - Fernández Retamar, Roberto, 1987 (Box-folder 2: 41)
  - Finkel, Bruria, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 2: 42)
  - Foppa, Alaide, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 43)
  - Forti, Liber and Anna, 1971-1999
    - 1971-1977 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - 1984-1999 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Futoransky, Luisa, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Gall, Norman, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - García Márquez, Gabriel, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - González Bermejo, Ernesto, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - González Moscoso, Hugo, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Gruner-Schlumberger, Anne, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Guardia y Font, Patricio de la, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Guevara Lynch, Ana María Erra de, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Guieler Tejada, Lidia, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Haggerty, Michael, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Héreld, Max, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Horta, Alejandro, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Jaffé, Angelina, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Jouffroy, Manina, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Jurquet, Henry, 1994 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Kalfon, Pierre, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Karvelis, Ugnė, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Lacy, Steve, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Landowski, Sophie, 1980 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Lang, Jack, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Lavandeira, Luis Alberto, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - Le Bot, Yvon, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Lira, Arturo, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Llerena, Edith, 1971-1989 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - López Junqué, Guillermo Fernando ("Chinolope"), 1988 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Luraschi, Tony and Susan, 1985 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - Manet, Eduardo, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - Mariotti-Luy, María, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 30)
  - Martínez, Nela, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 31)
  - Maspero, François, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 32)
  - Menchú, Rigoberta, 1982-1994 (Box-folder 3: 33)
  - Mendez, Denise, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 34)
  - Mitterrand, Danielle, 1986-1998 (Box-folder 3: 35)
  - Mitterrand, François, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 36)
  - Moleiro, Moisés, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 37)
  - Mora, Martha, 1991 (Box-folder 3: 38)
  - Munarriz, Valeria, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 3: 39)
  - Navarro, Bertha, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 40)
  - Paredes Bello, Fernando, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 41)
  - Peña, Rolando, 1973-1992 (Box-folder 3: 42)
  - Periáñez, Manuel, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 43)
  - Perret, Edith, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 3: 44)
  - Pinero, Maité, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 45)
  - Ponchelet, Danièle, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 3: 46)
  - Poniatowska, Elena, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 47)
  - Posse, Abel, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 3: 48)
  - Prado, Yolanda, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 3: 49)
  - Presno, Luis and Teresa, 1975 (Box-folder 3: 50)
  - Quezada, Delia, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 3: 51)
  - Quezada, Guido, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 52)
  - Ramia, Carmen, 1979 (Box-folder 3: 53)
  - Ramírez de Leon, Ricardo Arnoldo, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 3: 54)
  - Ramírez Ribes, María, 1992 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Revuelta, Nata, 1988 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Rivas, Henri, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Rodríguez, Mario Noel, 1992 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Rodríguez Piñero, Esperanza, 1988 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Rof Carballo, Juan, 1989 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Romanini, Maricrí, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Sabato, Ernesto, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Sánchez, Gustavo, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Sánchez, Rubén, 1972 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Sarduy, Mercy, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Sarduy, Severo, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Scherer Castillo, Hugo, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Senghor, Leopold Sedar, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Serrano, Pio E., 1991-1997 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Serrano Balasch, Ramón, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Siglo Veintiuno Editores (Jaime Labastida Ochoa), 1994 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Simon, Claude, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Soís, Marta, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Stefano, Victoria de, 1992 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Stone, Caroline, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Taborda, Luis, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Tartari, Manuela, 1985 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - Tax, Meredith, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - Téllez, Freddy, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - Texier, Philippe, 1986 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Timossi, Jorge, 1988 (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Tohá, Moi, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Torre, Javier, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Torres, Armando, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - Touraine, Alain, 1985 (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Triviño, Consuelo, 1994 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - Tusquets Editores (Nahir Gutiérrez, Beatriz de Houra, Antonio López Lamadrid, Christina Sánchez), 1996-1999 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - Tutino, Severino, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - Uribe, Armando, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Vaillant, Elisabeth, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Vargas Llosa, Mario, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - Vauzelle, Michel, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 38)
  - Velásquez, Lucila, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 39)
  - Verso Editions (Neil Belton, Misha Glenny), 1984 (Box-folder 4: 40)
  - Vidal, Guy, 1992 (Box-folder 4: 41)
  - Villa Rodríguez, José, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 4: 42)
  - Villalba Freire, Jorge, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 4: 43)
  - Villamarín Pulido, Luis Alberto, 2000 (Box-folder 4: 44)
  - Virgili, Carmen, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 45)
  - Zamora, José Rubén, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 46)
  - Zavaleta Mercado, René, 1969-1984 (Box-folder 4: 47)
  - Ziegler, Jean, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 48)
- Speeches and Writings, 1980-2004
  Contains articles, drafts of a monograph, an interview, and reviews, arranged chronologically.
  - Interviews with Cuban women, 1980
    - [?], Dora, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 49)
    - Dios, Gloria de, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 50)
    - Fonseca, A. N. Rosa, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 51)
    - Ruíz Prada, N. María, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 52)
    - Salinas, Vilma, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 53)
    - Santamaria, Haydee, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 54)
    - Veliz, Ester, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 55)
  - "Le récit d'une femme indienne, Rigoberta Menchú," Nouvel Observateur, 1982 April 24-30
    - Correspondence and typescript, 1982 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Printed copy, 1982 April 24-30 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Proposal for a film about the life of Rigoberta Menchú, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - With Rigoberta Menchú, Me llamo Rigoberta Menchú y así me nació la conciencia, 1983
    - Notes, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - First draft, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 5-9)
    - Second draft, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 10-11)
    - Second draft, 1983 (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
    - Reviews, 1983-1987
      - 1983 (Box-folder 6: 3-6)
      - 1984-1987 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - "La terrible et véridique histoire de Rigoberta Menchú," Nouvel Observateur, 1992 October 29-November 4 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - "Rigoberta Menchú, ruptura del discurso," Nexos, 1992 December (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - "Rigoberta Menchú, rupture du discours," Les Lettres françaises, 1992 December (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - "Rigoberta Menchú, el triunfo de los vencidos," El Nacional, 1992 December 13 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - With Rigoberta Menchú, "Ma grand'mère la Lune et mon père le Soleil,", 1993 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - "Rigoberta Menchú, la India rebelde," La Revista, 1996 April 14 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - "Deconstrucción de un mito,", 1996 October (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - "Las verdades de Rigoberta Menchú," Lateral, 1999 April (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - "Memoria, transmisíon e imagen del cuerpos,", 2000 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - "Entrevista a Serge Gruzinski,", 2000 January 11 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - "La excepción chilena,", 2001 May 20 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - "Perturbaciones cubanas en América Latina,", 2004 January (Box-folder 6: 19)
- Works Edited by Elisabeth Burgos-Debray, 1997-1999
  Contains notes, drafts of monographs, and reviews, arranged chronologically.
  - Alarcón Ramirez, Daniel "Benigno," Memorias de un soldado cubano, 1997
    - Notes, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - First draft, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 2-5)
    - Second draft, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 6-7)
    - Second draft, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
    - Reviews, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Masetti, Jorge, El furor y el delirio: itinerario de un hijo de la Revolución cubana, 1999
    - Notes, 1999 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - First draft, 1999 (Box-folder 8: 5-8)
    - Second draft, 1999 (Box-folder 8: 9-11)
- Régis Debray File, 1967-1971
  Contains appeals, biography, clippings, correspondence, declarations, journal, lists, notebook, petition, press conference materials, proposals, and transcripts, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Appeals made to the Bolivian government for the release of Régis Debray, 1969 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Biography of Régis Debray, 1967 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Clippings relating to the arrest, trial, imprisonment, and subsequent release of Régis Debray, 1967-1970
    - 1967 (Box-folder 9: 3-11)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 10: 1-14)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 11: 5-6)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1971
    - Burgos-Debray, Elisabeth, 1967-1970
      - Agence France-Presse (Hugo Alfonso Salmón), 1969 (Box-folder 11: 7)
      - Alexandre-Debray, Janine, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 11: 8)
      - Althusser, Louis, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 9)
      - Association Internationale des Juristes Démocrates (Suzanne Grégoire), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 11: 10)
      - Balibar, Étienne, 1970 (Box-folder 11: 11)
      - Blackburn, Robin, 1967 (Box-folder 11: 12)
      - Comitato per la liberazione di Régis Debray (Luca Curti, Guido Folloni), 1969 (Box-folder 11: 13)
      - Corghi, Corrado, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 11: 14)
      - Cortázar, Julio, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 15)
      - Debray, Gilles, 1967 (Box-folder 11: 16)
      - Debray, Régis, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 11: 17)
      - Fernández Retamar, Ricardo, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 18)
      - García, Virginia, 1970 (Box-folder 11: 19)
      - Di Marco, Luigi, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 20)
      - Domenach, J. M., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 11: 21)
      - Forti, Liber, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 11: 22)
      - Lallemand, Roger, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 23)
      - Lambroschini, Joseph, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 11: 24)
      - Lévi-Strauss, Claude, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 25)
      - Mendizabal-Moya, Jaime, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 11: 26)
      - Mouvement pour le désarmement, la paix et la liberté (Claude Bourdet), 1969 (Box-folder 11: 27)
      - Navarro, Marysa, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 28)
      - Neruda, Pablo, 1970 (Box-folder 11: 29)
      - Nuñez, Carlos, 1967 (Box-folder 11: 30)
      - Ovando Candía, Alfredo, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 31)
      - Prieto, Juan, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 32)
      - Rezvani, Serge and Danièle, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 33)
      - Saint Robert, Philippe de, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 34)
      - Sánchez, Gustavo, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11: 35)
      - Signoret, Simone, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 36)
      - Sinquin, Jean, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 37)
      - Unión de Mujeres de Bolivia, 1970 (Box-folder 11: 38)
      - Weitzman de Meza, Raquel, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 39)
      - Zwang, Gérard, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 40)
    - Debray, Georges and Janine Alexandre-Debray, 1967-1971
      - Letters of sympathy, 1967-1970
        - 1967 (Box-folder 12: 1-12)
        - 1967 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
        - 1968 (Box-folder 13: 3)
        - 1969 (Box-folder 13: 4)
        - 1970 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      - Aguilera, Roqué, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 6)
      - Alexandre, Christiane, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 7)
      - Anaya Arze, Ricardo, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 8)
      - Arrighi, Paul, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 9)
      - Asturias, Miguel Angel, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 10)
      - Baras, Gilbert, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 11)
      - Barrault, Jean-Louis, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 12)
      - Barrientos Ortuño, René, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 13)
      - Barruel, [?], 1968 (Box-folder 13: 14)
      - Basdevant, Jean, 1968 (Box-folder 13: 15)
      - Bayle, Henry and Jutta, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 13: 16)
      - Bianchi, Mario, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13: 17)
      - Bois, Étienne, 1968 (Box-folder 13: 18)
      - Bondoux, René, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 19)
      - Burgos-Debray, Elisabeth, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 13: 20)
      - Chaban Delmas, Jacques, 1971 (Box-folder 13: 21)
      - Comité international de la Croix-Rouge (P. Gaillard), 1969 (Box-folder 13: 22)
      - Corghi, Corrado, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 13: 23)
      - Debray, Gilles and Dominique, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 24)
      - Debray, Henri-Robert, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13: 25)
      - Debray, Jean-Robert, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 26)
      - Debray, Pierre, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 27)
      - Debray, Régis, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 28)
      - Delgadillo Olivares, Hugo, 1970 (Box-folder 13: 29)
      - Diaz Mondéjar, Jacinta, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 13: 30)
      - Diedisheim, Jean, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 31)
      - Espejo Novoa, Paz, 1970 (Box-folder 13: 32)
      - Figaro, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13: 33)
      - Gaulle, Charles de, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 34)
      - Geismar, Yvonne, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 35)
      - Ginestié, Philippe, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 36)
      - Hader, Gisela, 1968 (Box-folder 13: 37)
      - Jurgensen, J. D., 1967 (Box-folder 13: 38)
      - Lacan, Jacques, 1970 (Box-folder 13: 39)
      - Lallemand, Roger, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13: 40)
      - Lambroschini, Joseph, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 13: 41)
      - Latour, Jacqueline de, 1968 (Box-folder 13: 42)